<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Code for Thought]]></title>
  <link href="http://hannahlw.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hannahlw.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-29T21:44:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://hannahlw.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hannah Westheimer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So You Want to Be a Web-Developer?]]></title>
    <link href="http://hannahlw.github.io/blog/2015/03/29/so-you-want-to-be-a-web-developer/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T21:20:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hannahlw.github.io/blog/2015/03/29/so-you-want-to-be-a-web-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow is my first day of The Flatiron Program and I expect the next three months will be super intense and, I hope, super rewarding in the end.</p>

<p>My background is not in code. In fact I literally had to google “what is code?” when I first started. I found web-development when I moved to Philly with my husband who just started vet school and I was left without a close group of friends and without an interesting job (I nannied which was so fun but limited my conversations with adults even more). I had just binged watched all of Gossip Girl and I realized I needed to stimulate my brain somehow or I was going to get lost in this world of Netflix and my comfy couch.</p>

<iframe src="//giphy.com/embed/11AhuUM0WCwsms?html5=true" width="480" height="260" frameBorder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>I started googling fun stimulating things to do and I stumbled across <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/hannah.westheimergmail.com">Codecademy</a> and through “learning a new skill and being able to build something in the process &ndash; this could be really cool”. I had fun messing around and when I told my brother who is engaged in the NY tech scene he said something like “you know you can actually make a career out of that? Check out The Flatiron School.” I did and the rest is history.</p>

<p>After about a year of taking classes on and off through Codecademy, Treehouse and Girl Develop It, code is thrilling and fun when I get it however, most of the time it is still really hard and confusing. I am super excited for the chance to learn with other people, have instructors, and a curriculum to steer me in the right direction.</p>

<p>Here’s to the next three months!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
